<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Books Read</title>
    <link>//localhost:54970/books/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Books Read</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:54970/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Pachinko</title>
      <link>//localhost:54970/books/20250106-pachinko/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:54970/books/20250106-pachinko/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I think I&amp;rsquo;m probably underestimating this book, but while some parts of it engaged me thoughroughly and emotionally, other parts that moved quicker through time, characters and locations left me cold. I really enjoyed the parts where we stayted with a story and character for a while, and the writing drew me in to the story really well, but I almost stopped reading during about three-quarters of the way through as I felt like we were just jumping five years with every chapter between characters I didn&amp;rsquo;t really care about. I&amp;rsquo;m glad I stuck with the book. I did enjoy it and if that&amp;rsquo;s the price to pay for such an ambitious work then I&amp;rsquo;m fine with that.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Red Notice</title>
      <link>//localhost:54970/books/20241128-red-notice/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:54970/books/20241128-red-notice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This book wooed me in with tails of financial daring-do in late 90&amp;rsquo;s/early 2000&amp;rsquo;s Moscow, but before I knew it I was reading about corruption, imprisonment and murder. I felt like this book gave me a small sense of the Russion mindset, and perhaps helps me to understand a little about the current situation in the country, and how it arose and has been maintained. I have to admit enjoying the first half of the book more, which covered the author getting established and starting out in Russia. The last quarter, which focuses on efforts to get some kind of justice for one of the author&amp;rsquo;s colleagues is by it&amp;rsquo;s nature least entertaining, but by that time I was sufficiently invested in the characters involved to remain engaged right to the end.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>American Dirt</title>
      <link>//localhost:54970/books/20241109-american-dirt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:54970/books/20241109-american-dirt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a work of fiction that offers me a window into a world that I will never experience, this book is a success on every level. At times I found the writing a little &lt;q&gt;on the nose&lt;/q&gt;, and some of the plot devices a bit too much, but honestly, that doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter. The book totally gripped me and didn&amp;rsquo;t let go. It forced me to think more deeply about a subject that I had only considered in an abstact way. As a white male living in a comfortable country, I feel like I am absolutely the target audience for this book, and perhaps because of this some of the cultural context is simplified and occasionally I felt like I was engaging with literary clickbait, but I don&amp;rsquo;t care. I hope that I will never think about people who migrate in the same way after reading this.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Girl with the Dragon Tattoo</title>
      <link>//localhost:54970/books/20241021-girl-dragon-tattoo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:54970/books/20241021-girl-dragon-tattoo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I inherited a copy from a friend&amp;rsquo;s mum who was having a clearout, and thought I&amp;rsquo;d give this one another read to see how it holds up. Very well is the answer. The characters are wonderfully developed, and great fun. I love the setting, and it seems a great book to read as Autumn is comming on. I love the descriptions of the technology people are using - CD ROMS, CDs, iBooks, but somehow the use of these terms seems to place the story more firmly in the era it was written rather than undermine the narrative. The second of the triology is waiting for me, and I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Year of the Locust</title>
      <link>//localhost:54970/books/20240823-the-year-of-the-locust/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:54970/books/20240823-the-year-of-the-locust/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know what happened here. The first 80% of the book was an engaging, thriller, typical of what I would expect from this kind of genre. Actually, not typical, slightly better in fact. I enjoyed the premise, the locations and even the characters. But, and this is a big but, I feel like the author just lost interest in the last 15% of the book. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t the massive genre switch that upset me, which I thought the author pulled off pretty well considering the shift from espionage thriller to science-fiction is not a small leap. But rather the massive plot holes, assumptions and contrivances that came with it. If I hadn&amp;rsquo;t already read about 550 pages I would have stopped reading. The only reasonable explanation I can think of is the author was on a deadline to deliver, and just chucked out whatever passed the increadably low bar set by their editor. A real dissapointment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Damascus Station</title>
      <link>//localhost:54970/books/20240818-damascus-station/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:54970/books/20240818-damascus-station/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I did enjoy this book, mostly. The plot was good, and didn&amp;rsquo;t require too much of a suspension of disbelief. I liked that the book communicated the context and claustrophobia that I imagine comes with working in a country like Syria, and it appears to give a good portrate of Damascus. That said, the book seemed to be clearly aimed at middle aged, American males, and I did find the lengthy, slightly provocative descriptions of the heroine were laid on a bit thick, but it was nothing I couldn&amp;rsquo;t live with. The book helped pass an eight hour plane journey nicely, and if your in the mood for an engaging and enjoyable thriller that doesn&amp;rsquo;t ask too much of you this would fit the bill nicely.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nine Lives: My Time As MI6&#39;s Top Spy Inside al-Qaeda</title>
      <link>//localhost:54970/books/20240808-nine-lives/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:54970/books/20240808-nine-lives/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An interesting and insightful book from someone who operated at the highest levels of al-Qaeda. I picked this book up after hearing his story serialised on a podcast. The authors do a good job of not sensationalising the activities, while retaining enough description to remain engaging. It&amp;rsquo;s is a non-fiction book, that deals with a serious topic, but the podcast may have led me to expect a more &lt;em&gt;&amp;lsquo;entertaining&amp;rsquo;&lt;/em&gt; read. On reflection, the book is better off as it is: a serious, factual account without any unnecessary window-dressing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Wager</title>
      <link>//localhost:54970/books/20240729-the-wager/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:54970/books/20240729-the-wager/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I picked this one up at random based on the staff recommendations at our local library. I really enjoyed the well researched depictions and descriptions of life in the British navy and at sea during this period of history. There was a large cast of characters and it is a credit to the author that I never felt lost or wondered who was who, despite the various splits and factions that make up a large part of the story. For once I also appreciated that the book didn&amp;rsquo;t include maps of the locations where the main event took place. This left me with only a rough idea of where the events took place which left me in much the same position as the characters (I looked it up afterwards though!) I wondered if this was intentional. An enjoyable, well researched, excellent read.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Smiley&#39;s People</title>
      <link>//localhost:54970/books/20240719-smileys-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:54970/books/20240719-smileys-people/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The final instalment of the &lt;em&gt;&amp;lsquo;Karla Triology&amp;rsquo;&lt;/em&gt; that I&amp;rsquo;ve thoroughly enjoyed reading this year. Once again, George Smiley starts pulling at a thread that unravels a plot that that slowly emerges over the book&amp;rsquo;s 335 pages. Gradually, piece-by-piece the fog clears as he homes in on the achilles heel of his arch rival. By the end we arrive at a wonderfully understated climax wondering quite how we managed to end up where we did. I really enjoyed this book, and am pleased that the author returned to form, moving on from the faster paced, more exotic &lt;a href=&#34;//localhost:54970/books/20240614-the-honourable-schoolboy/&#34;&gt;The Honourable Schoolboy&lt;/a&gt;, almost meeting the amazingly high standard set at the trilogy&amp;rsquo;s outset in &lt;a href=&#34;//localhost:54970/books/20240221-tinker-tailor-soldier-spy/&#34;&gt;Tinker, Tailor, Soldier, Spy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Honourable Schoolboy</title>
      <link>//localhost:54970/books/20240614-the-honourable-schoolboy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:54970/books/20240614-the-honourable-schoolboy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The second in the &lt;em&gt;&amp;lsquo;Karla Triology&amp;rsquo;&lt;/em&gt; that follows on from the wonderful &lt;a href=&#34;//localhost:54970/books/20240221-tinker-tailor-soldier-spy/&#34;&gt;Tinker, Tailor, Soldier, Spy&lt;/a&gt;. This is a long, complicated book that requires attention, and rewards the reader with a great cast of characters and a subtle plot (at times perhaps too subtle?) that crescendos over almost 700 pages to a thrilling climax. The slow build of the story meant that, at times, I could only really understand where I was in the story, not how I&amp;rsquo;d got there, which I enjoyed. However, whereas in Tinker Tailor the seriousness and impact of the situation was clear from the start, I never really appreciated the value of the &lt;em&gt;&amp;lsquo;prize&amp;rsquo;&lt;/em&gt; in this book sufficiently to get as emotionally invested as I&amp;rsquo;d have liked.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Escape Artist</title>
      <link>//localhost:54970/books/20240412-the-escape-artist/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:54970/books/20240412-the-escape-artist/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Honestly, I would have never chosen to read a book about Auschwitz on purpose, but I&amp;rsquo;m glad that I ended up reading one. This book did an amazing trick of giving me some idea what happened there through the lens of the amazing life story of Rudolf Vrba, the first Jew to successfully escape from the prison. In a strange way the fact that the horror of the situation wasn&amp;rsquo;t the focus on the book made it all the more disturbing. Absolutely unimaginable things are described as part of every day life. Truely, truely shocking. A very good read. I didn&amp;rsquo;t rate it higher, as I felt the final chapters after the escape went on too long.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Sisters Brothers</title>
      <link>//localhost:54970/books/20240330-the-sisters-brothers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:54970/books/20240330-the-sisters-brothers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Oh the joys of getting back to a simple well written story after the trials of &lt;a href=&#34;//localhost:54970/books/20240316-victory-city/&#34;&gt;Victory City&lt;/a&gt;. I say simple, but I was frequently, surprised and charmed by the turns the story took as the brothers made their way accross America. I felt a real affection for Eli, and his internal turmoil, which developed  wonderfully as the story progressed. An enjoyable, fun read, that was never overwhelmed by the violence it contained.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Victory City</title>
      <link>//localhost:54970/books/20240316-victory-city/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:54970/books/20240316-victory-city/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Maybe I missed something here, but this book just didn&amp;rsquo;t work for me. It almost felt to me like an outline of a book, without the flesh and depth that have made the author&amp;rsquo;s writing a joy for me to read in the past. I made it though about 300 of the 384 pages, and, once I&amp;rsquo;d got over not finishing it, all I felt was relief.  I&amp;rsquo;m going to give Midnight&amp;rsquo;s Children, which I remember loving, another try and see what I make of it this time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>But What Can I Do?</title>
      <link>//localhost:54970/books/20240218-but-what-can-i-do/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:54970/books/20240218-but-what-can-i-do/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I really wanted to like this book, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t. I enjoy the informal tone of Alastair Campbell on his podcast with Rory Stewart, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t warm to it at all in the witten form. I found that 95% of the book was the warm up to what I actually wanted to learn from this book: what I can I to help make politics better in this country. I hope that it serves to motivate people to get involved in politics, but this one wasn&amp;rsquo;t for me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tinker Tailor Soldier Spy</title>
      <link>//localhost:54970/books/20240221-tinker-tailor-soldier-spy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:54970/books/20240221-tinker-tailor-soldier-spy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This was a great read. I finished it too late last night. Probably too late to properly enjoy the last few pages, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to stop until I&amp;rsquo;d finished — I had to go back and read the last couple of pages twice. I just loved the ending. I loved the minimal exposition throughout the book — a proper masterpiece of &lt;em&gt;&amp;lsquo;show, don&amp;rsquo;t tell&amp;rsquo;&lt;/em&gt; writing exemplified with the book&amp;rsquo;s final couple of sentences. An intelligent, thoughtful thriller. I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to reading more of John le Carré&amp;rsquo;s work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Politics on the Edge</title>
      <link>//localhost:54970/books/20240129-politics-on-the-edge/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:54970/books/20240129-politics-on-the-edge/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have a bit of a man crush on Rory Stewart and was excited to receive this book as my leaving gift. I enjoyed it, although it is a bit of a depressing take on the state of UK politics and the way things work — and things have only got worse since Rory’s time. The book was split into three main acts focusing on: getting elected and representing Cumbria; time spent as junior and then more senior government minister; and Rory’s run for leader of the Conservative Party. It’s a testament to the writing that I was rooting for Rory to win the contest even though we all know the outcome. Well worth a read.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Make the Best Coffee at Home</title>
      <link>//localhost:54970/books/20240115-how-to-make-the-best-coffee-at-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:54970/books/20240115-how-to-make-the-best-coffee-at-home/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A really well-thought-out and presented guide to making better coffee. The author has a great way of talking about what can be a pretty pretentious subject in a down to earth and accessible manner. It&amp;rsquo;s encouraged me to rethink a couple of aspects of my brewing process. I didn&amp;rsquo;t realise how much has changed, and how many fads have come and gone in the last 20 years or so of coffee making. It&amp;rsquo;s reassuring that everyone is making it up as we go along.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Hero in France</title>
      <link>//localhost:54970/books/20240118-a-hero-in-france/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:54970/books/20240118-a-hero-in-france/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A welcome relief after &lt;a href=&#34;//localhost:54970/books/20240106-the-road/&#34;&gt;The Road&lt;/a&gt;. I enjoyed it but still quite intense in its own right, understated way. I found it more like a series of insights into what life might have been like in occupied France than story a typical narrative arc, but the connections between the sections were well maintained and it never felt disjointed. Another good read from Alan Furst —but probably not his best.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Road</title>
      <link>//localhost:54970/books/20240106-the-road/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:54970/books/20240106-the-road/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What to say about this book that&amp;rsquo;s not already been said in a much better way than I could ever put it? This was a third attempt at reading it for me and I loved it, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t put it down. This time something just clicked. I read many of the paragraphs more than once as there was so much nestled into the few words they contained. A brilliant piece of writing and once I&amp;rsquo;ve recovered I&amp;rsquo;ll have another go at Blood Meridian (which I&amp;rsquo;ve also failed at twice).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Age of Vice</title>
      <link>//localhost:54970/books/20231220-age-of-vice/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:54970/books/20231220-age-of-vice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A good fun novel that I really enjoyed. I have a soft spot for books set in India and this one didn&amp;rsquo;t disappoint. There was more going on than I realised and I perhaps should have paid more attention in at the earlier sections of the book to get the most out of its structure. All in all, a great story (perhaps a little long&amp;hellip;), but fun characters and one that I might read again as I continue to indulge my soft spot for stories based in India.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Killing Thatcher: The IRA, the Manhunt and the Long War on the Crown</title>
      <link>//localhost:54970/books/20231219-killing-thatcher/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:54970/books/20231219-killing-thatcher/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An interesting read. I especially enjoyed both the history and context the author provided for the Brighton bombing, which I can vaguely remember seeing or hearing about on the news (I think — I&amp;rsquo;d have been about seven). The book gave a nice insight into how an organisation like the IRA might work, and how its members would have perceived the UK, and it&amp;rsquo;s government. I also enjoyed that it tied in nicely with the BBC series &amp;lsquo;The Gold&amp;rsquo;, which was good fun, as the lead detective went on to lead that investigation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
